Guide to the Willard Livingstone Beard Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Willard Livingstone Beard Family Papers
1892-1964
RG 108
Yale University Divinity School Library
6
(13 boxes)
Correspondence, diaries, writings, and collected material provide valuable documentation of the work of Willard Livingstone Beard and his family. Beard was a missionary in China from 1894 to 1941, serving in Fukien Province under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions and the YMCA.
Beard, Willard Livingstone, 1865-1947
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Geraldine Beard (original collection, ca. 1993) and the Beard family (addendum, 2006-2007, 2010).
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Willard Livingstone Beard was born in Shelton, Connecticut in 1865, son of Oliver Gould Beard and Nancy Maria Nicols Beard. Following his marriage to Ellen Kinney in 1894, he served the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions' Foochow mission for over forty years (1894-1941). The Beards had six children: Phebe (1895-1925), Myron Gould (1896-1974), Geraldine (1898-1993), Dorothy (1901-1991), Marjorie (1906-1995), and Kathleen (1908-2004). During the period 1905-1910, Beard was released by the ABCFM to set up and head a branch of the YMCA in Fukien province. Beard died in 1947 and Ellen Kinney Beard died in 1953.
Willard Beard had two sisters, Flora and Mary, who also worked in China. Flora lived in Foochow from October of 1906 to July of 1909; she was not officially a missionary but taught missionary children. In 1914, Flora and her youngest sister Mary Louse Beard left the U.S. for Peking where they founded the North China American School (NCAS) for missionary children. The sisters were at NCAS from 1914 to 1920.
Scope and Contents
The Willlard L. Beard Family Papers consist of five linear feet of material divided into six series. The papers provide valuable early documentation of ABCFM and YMCA work in the Foochow area. They include not only Beard's personal correspondence and diaries, but also collected report and printed material documenting mission work in Fukien province. A substantial amount of material has been added to this collection since it was microfilmed as part of the Adam Matthew "China Through Western Eyes" collection and the box and folder numbers have been revised. The Beard Family Papers complement other collections at the Yale Divinity Library that document mission work in the Fukien Province, including the papers of Emily Susan Hartwell, Eva Asher, Charles and Mary Storrs, and others.
Series I, Correspondence, consists primarily of family correspondence, with a small amount of correspondence addressed to non-family. The family correspondence is arranged in chronological order. The original collection contained forty-nine letters of Beard, one from Ellen Kinney Beard and two from Phebe Kinney Beard. In 2006, the Beard family donated more than one hundred additional letters. Transcripts and abstracts of the added letters have been prepared by Jana Jackson, wife of the grandson of Kathleen Beard Elmer; they are filed in the same folders as the original letters. Electronic copies of the letters are also available. Many of the added letters were in the possession of Donald MacInnis for a number of years, as he did research for his book, China Chronicles from a Lost Time: the Min River Journals. The letters are primarily written from Foochow of Kuliang (a summer resort for missionaries in the mountains) to family memgbers in the U.S. Letters addressed to "Friends at home", "Home friends", and "Folks at home" have been included in the Family Correspondence sub-series. The letters give substantial accounts of the Beards' daily work and touch on political events and social issues in China.
Among the newly added correspondence in Series I are substantive letters written by Willard Beard's sisters Flora and Mary. Besides describing their day-to-day work at the North China American School in Peking (Beijing), they describe trips they took in China, the funeral procession of Yuan Shi Kai, the political situation, and rest and relaxation at the seaside resort of Pei Tai Ho.
The Diaries and Journals of Series II include three daily diaries of the Imperial English and Chinese Diary format, which provide regular accounts of Beard's activities and acquaintances, and two accounts of trips taken by Beard. A daily account of a trip from Foochow to Shaowu and back (1906 Nov - 1907 Jan) provides a valuable detailed account of typical missionary work.
Writings in Series II include Beard's account of a dispute between two villages near Foochow and the visit of E. Stanley Jones to Foochow. Collected Material in Series III documents the work of the American Board in Fukien Province and Foochow College. Photographs, biographical information, and memorabilia, and a set of compiled documents complete the collection.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1894-1944, n.d.
II. Diaries and Journals, 1895-1907, 1928.
III. Writings, 1915-1941, n.d.
IV. Collected Material, 1896-1947, n.d.
V. Photographs, 1901-1956, n.d.
VI. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1900-1964.
VII. Compilation of Documents, 1892-1950s
Missions -- China; Beard, Willard Livingstone, 1865-1947; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
- Correspondence, 1892-1944; Series I
  - Family
    Scope and Contents
    Digital copies of transcribed correspondence are available.
    - Five letters from Ellen Kinney (EK) to Willard Livingstone Beard (WLB) regarding visits in Connecticut, 1892 November - 1893 April (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Four letters from WLB to EK at Oberlin College; one letter from Ruth Beard to EK, 1893 October - December (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Seven letters from WLB to EK regarding studies, preaching, application to Mission Board, 1894 January - February (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Four letters from EK to WLB; regarding Student Volunteer Movement convention, application to Mission Board; one letter from WLB to IK, 1894 March - April (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Four letters from EK to WLB; two letters WLB to EK telling of bicycle trips, anticipating her return home, 1894 May - June (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Three letters from Ellen Kinney Beard (ELK) to home folks from Foochow; four letters from Willard L. Beard (WLB) to home, incl. re. birth of daughter, Phebe, 1894 Dec 15- 1895 Jun 16 (Box 1, Folder 1b)
    - Five letters from WLB in Foochow to home; re. cholera outbreak and massacre in Kucheng, 1895 Jul 28- Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Six letters from WLB to home; tells of death of missionary friend from cancer, 1896 Jan 7- Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Five letters from WLB to home including need of women missionaries to minister to women; Ellen and Phebe move to Kuliang resort, 1896 Apr 8-Jun 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Six letters from WLB to home, one from EKB; missionaries living in mountains during heat, purchase of land, 1896 Jul 13-Sep 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Seven letters from WLB to home, one from EKB; tells of birth of son: Myron Gould, WLB visits Shanghai, 1896 Oct 1- Dec 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Eight letters from WLB to home; Christmas celebrations, children doing well, 1897 Jan 3- May 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Eight letters WLB to EKB while they are in mountains, 1897 Jun 6- Jun 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Seven letters WLB to home; enjoying new home in Kuliang, one letter WLB to EKB, 1897 Jul 5- Sep 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Four letters WLB to home- one EKB to home; regarding Chinese Anti-Footbinding Society, 1897 Oct 3- Dec 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Eight letters WLB to home; regarding recent trip with another missionary, notice of increase in Western influence in China, 1898 Jan 1- Apr 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Six letters WLB to regarding move to mountains, birth of second daughter, Geraldine, 1898 May 1- Aug 25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Six letters WLB to home regarding typhoons, Ellen teaching music in Seminary, new missonaries expected, one letter from brother James, 1898 Sep 4- Dec 25 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Six letters WLB to home; relaxing trip on houseboat, 1899 Jan 22- Apr 23 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Nine letters WLB to home; regarding floods, rain, illness, 1899 May 7- Sep 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Six letters WLB to home- one by EKB; plans for new residence, 1899 Oct 8- Dec 24 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Seven letters WLB to home; regarding possible devil possession, 1900 Jan 21- May 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Ten letters WLB to home; including regarding Boxer Rebellion, 1900 Jun 3- Aug 26 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Nine letters WLB to home; regarding 6th wedding anniversary, political unrest, 1900 Sep 2- Oct 28 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Seven letters WLB to home-one EKB; officials executed for murder of foreigner, 1900 Nov-Dec (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Seven letters WLB to home, 1901 Jan-Mar (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Seven letters WLB to home; including plague and man using opium, 1901 Apr- Jun (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Twelve letters WLB- Foochow- to home; regarding floods, plague, move into new house, John R. Mott visit, 1901 Jul 7- Dec 21 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Thirteen letters WLB to home; speaks of new daughter- Dorothy, concern for drought, 1902 Jan 19- Jun 22 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Nine letters WLB to home; regarding plague and cholera, awaiting decision regarding leaving American Board to work for YMCA, 1902 Jul 13- Oct 26 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Four letters WLB to home; eight week trip to Shaowu and villages, 1902 Nov 9 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Three letters EKB; regarding WLB's trip to Shaowu, Four letters WLB regarding family returning to US, 1903 Jan 3- Apr 8 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Five letters Flora (sister) traveling in Europe, Letters from WLB and daughter traveling in Europe, 1904 Jul, Oct-Dec (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Eight letters and postcards family returning to China, 1905 Jan-Mar (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Nine letters WLB from Foochow to home, two letters from son and one from EKB to home, 1905 Apr-Aug (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - One letter from EKB to home regarding illness, seven letters- WLB- improved health, illness among missionaries (WLB now working with YMCA), 1905 Sep 5- Dec 7 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Eight letters WLB to home; including birth of daughter Marjorie, sister Flora coming to China, 1906 Jan 9- Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Seven letters WLB to home; regarding YMCA work, two letters from Flora- traveling; one letter from Phebe to grandmother, 1906 May 14- Oct 26 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Four letters from Flora to home- one letter WLB; travel journal, Shaowu trip, 1906 Nov (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Six letters from Flora (in Foochow) to home; six from WLB to home, one by (Myron) Gould to grandma, 1906 Dec- 1907 Jan (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Four letters from Flora to home, Two WLB to EKB; while he is at conference in Japan, Two WLB to home, one Gould to Aunt, 1907 Feb- Apr (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Five letters from Flora to home, three letters WLB tells of conferences attended over 2 months, moved into new house, 1907 Feb- Apr (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Three letters WLB to home, four letters Flora to home, 1907 May-Jun (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Six letters WLB to home; regarding work in YMCA, two letters from Flora and one from Phebe, 1907 Jul-Dec (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Three letters WLB to home; four from Flora, 1908 May- Jun (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Five letters from Flora regarding travels in Japan; five letters WLB to home, birth of daughter Kathleen, 1908 Jul-Aug (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Four letters WLB to home, three WLB to EKB; tells of fire in YMCA tent in Amoy; two from Flora to home, 1908 Sep- Dec (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Four letteers WLB from Foochow to home, three letters from Flora to home; plans to return to US, 1909 Feb- Mar (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Three letters WLB to home; regarding American Board wanting him back from YMCA; two letters from Flora, 1909 Apr- Jul (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Three letters WLB to home from conference in Swatow and Kuliang; one letter from Phebe to home, One from EKB to WLB, 1909 Aug-Sep (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Three letters WLB to home; regarding new job at ABCFM in New York, preparations for going home, letters also from Phebe and Dorothy to home, 1909 Oct-Dec (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Seven letters WLB- four to children- two to his mother; has returned to Foochow College, 1912 Aug- 1913 Dec (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Six letters WLB to his children, 1914 Mar-Jun (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Three letters WLB to home, six letters from Flora and Mary traveling to China, 1914 Aug (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Four letters WLB to home; tells of typhoons, Seven letters from Mary and Flora; regarding school, 1914 Sep (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Three letters WLB- one to son; regarding Sherwood Eddy evangelistic campaign; seven letters from Flora and Mary describing excursions, 1914 Oct-Nov (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Eight letters WLB to home, Three letters from Mary and Flora regarding Christmas, 1915 Jan-Feb (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - One letter WLB regarding Foochow College large enrollment, Three from Flora and Mary in Peking, 1915 Mar (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Three letters from WLB to sisters and daughter; four from Mary and Flora to home; concern regarding Japan, 1915 Apr (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Four letters WLB, six from Mary and Flora, 1915 May-Jun (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Five letters from Mary and Flora, 1915 Jul (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Seven letters from Flora and Mary; leaving Peking, two from WLB, 1915 Aug (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Three letters from WLB; four from Flora and Mary teaching again in Fongchou, 1915 Sep (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Five letters from WLB (2 to children); five from Mary and Flora, 1915 Oct (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Three letters from WLB to children; four from Mary and Flora, 1915 Nov-Dec (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Five letters from WLB planning return to US; five from Flora and Mary, 1916 Jan (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Five letters from WLB to home; nine from Mary and Flora, 1916 Feb-Mar (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - One letter EKB to daughter; nine from Mary and Flora, 1916 Apr-May (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Four letters from WLB; received ? degree from Oberlin, plans to return to China with EKB and 2 daughters; nine letters from Flora and Mary; regarding school and funeral of Pres. Yuan-shih Kai, 1916 Jun-Jul (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Two letters from WLB; regarding trip; one letter from Kathleen to Phebe; seven from Mary and Flora, 1916 Aug-Sep (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Five letters from WLB to home and children, EKB to daughter; six from Mary and Flora regarding school, 1916 Oct-Nov (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Four letters from WLB; tells of fires and great damage in Foochow; six from Mary and Flora, 1916 Dec (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Five from WLB to daughters and mother; six from Flora and Mary, 1917 Jan-Feb (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Five letters from WLB; four from Mary and Flora, 1917 Mar-Apr (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Three letters from WLB; three from Mary and Flora; regarding death of their sister Ruth, 1917 May-Jun (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Three letters from WLB to daughters; three from Mary and Flora to home, 1917 Jul-Aug (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Four letters from WLB to daughters, 1917 Sep-Dec (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Seven letters WLB to children giving advice and also regarding his travels; two between siblings, 1918 Feb-Dec (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Six letters from WBLB to daughter Phebe; (WLB in US); one to Dorothy; one letter from Phebe to relatives, 1919 Jan-1920 Mar (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Five letters from WLB to children; regarding their illnesses; one letter from Phebe (1923); teaching in Foochow, 1924 Aug-1925 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Four letters from WLB; regarding Phebe's serious illness; four from EKB; traveling to China; one from Phebe, 1925 Jun-Dec (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Two letters from Dorothy to sisters, EKB to children describing daughter Phebe's illness and death; Gould to his sisters; three letters from WLB and EKB to children, 1926 Jan-Apr (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Six letters from WLB to home; regarding his father's death and Dorothy's engagement; one letter to girls from Aunt Mary; one from Dorothy to sisters, 1926 May-Sep (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Three letters from WLB to family; six letters between sisters; two from Aunt Mary to Geraldine, 1926 Oct-Dec (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Four letters of sisters; Dorothy married; one from Gould; his engagement broken; one from WLB; plans to return to US, 1927 Feb-Sep (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Four letters from WLB to Geraldine from Shelton, CT, 1928 Jan-May (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Four letters from EKB and WLB to children; on shipboard returning to China; five from China, 1928 Oct-Dec (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Four letters from WLB to home; nine letters between siblings; Gould engaged, 1929 Feb-Aug (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Three from WLB to family; three from Dorothy to siblings; regarding Gould's flying and her first plane ride, 1929 Sep-Oct (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Four letters from WLB and EKB to family; five siblings letters, 1929 Nov-Dec (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Eight letters from WLB to family; EKB had typhoid fever; one letter from WLB to EKB; four letters siblings, 1930 Jan-Apr (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Seven letters from WLB to home; regarding fighting between bandits and government, Gould married; six letters from Dorothy to Geraldine; regarding parents coming to US and WLB to have surgery, 1930 Jun-Dec (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Seven sibling letters; Gould has daughter, 1931 Jan-Aug (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Nine sibling letters; three from WLB to daughter Geraldine; leaving for China, 1931 Sep (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Seven sibling letters; Kathleen in Utah unhappy on her teaching; two from WLB to family back in Foochow, 1931 Oct-Dec (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Five sibling letters; three from WLB regarding work in China, 1932 Jan-Mar (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Five sibling letters; one from EKB to son; three from WLB; appointed Assistant General Secretary of Mid-Fukien Synod CCC, 1932 Apr-Aug (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Two letters from WLB to home, 1932 Mar (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Eight sibling letters; Kathleen expecting second child, 1937 May-Fall (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Two from EKB to daughter, Three from WLB to daughters and family; traveling in Florida and baby Cynthia born, 1937 Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Letters from Kathleen, Ellen, WLB; raising rabbits, Gould tells of daughter Hazel's injuries as she was hit by a bus, 1938 Jan-Apr (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Two letters from WLB to Geraldine; six sibling letters, 1938 May-Nov (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Five letters from WLB to family, WLB and EKB back to Foochow, 1939 Mar-Nov (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - WLB; six letters to family; about hernia surgery and working in Ing Tai- high prices, 1940 Apr-Jun (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Six letters from WLB to family and friends; review of work in Ing Tai; three from Kathleen to Jerry; daughter Marjorie married, 1940 Jul-Nov (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Four letters from WLB; regarding bomb, bandits, and returning to US; one letter each Phebe and Mary, 1941 Jan-Aug (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Seven letters from WLB to Geraldine; back in CT; three sibling letters, 1941 Oct-Dec (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Nine letters various family members, 1942 Jan (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Four letters from WLB to Geraldine; six from Kathleen to Jerry, 1942 Feb-Aug (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Six letters WLB and EKB to Geraldine; six sibling letters, 1942 Sep-Dec (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Eleven letters from WLB and siblings to Geraldine; new baby and problems of government rationing, 1943 Jan-Feb (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Ten letters WLB and others, 1943 Mar-Apr (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - WLB and EKB and others; ten letters about everyday life, 1943 May-Jul (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - Ten letters from WLB to Geraldine; regarding farm life; five to GB from siblings and aunt and uncle, 1943 Aug-Dec (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Three letters WLB; tells of their 50th wedding anniversary celebration; one letter Ginny to Geraldine, 1944 Jan-Jul (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - General Correspondence
    - One letter to WLB's father, Others from John R. Mott, A.J. Osgood, L. Hodous, WLB to Sturges and Mott, 1898-1907 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Including from Hu Nguk Sing, to WE Strong, E. Smith, W.H. Topping, H.V. Lacy, Chen Ting Chun, 1916-1930 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Including from Leonard Christian, WLB to AR Keplar, WLB to E.C. Lobenstine, Grace Smith, E.W. Smith, 1930-1940? (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Other letters
    - Five letters to Geraldine from various people, 1940-1943 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Including Dwight and Goddard, Two to Flora Beard, one to Phebe K. Beard, 1901-1917 (Box 7, Folder 115)
- Diaries and Journals, 1895-1907, 1928; Series II
  - Willard L. Beard
    - Imperial English and Chinese Diary format, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Imperial English and Chinese Diary format, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Imperial English and Chinese Diary format, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - Account of voyage from Foochow to Connecticut, via Europe, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Account of trip from Foochow to Shaowu and back, 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Geraldine Beard
    - Diary, 1928 January - March (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Writings, Series III
  - Of Willard L. Beard
    - Account of dispute between two villages near Foochow, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Annual Report of WLB, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - A Missionary's Thoughts after Thirty-Eight Years in China (from Chinese Recorder, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Some Thoughts on Re-thinking Missions, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Dr. E. Stanley Jones in Foochow, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Of Ellen Kinney Beard
    - Account of invasion of Foochow, 1941 Apr 20 (Box 8, Folder 122)
- Collected Material, 1896-1947; Series IV
  - Re. ABCFM work in Fukien
    - Reports of Foochow Mission, 1896, 1898-1902 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Minutes of Foochow Mission, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Reports of Ing Hok Station, 1897, 1899, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Reports of Work for Women and Children, 1897, 1899, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Reports of Ponasang Hospital, Foochow, 1897, 1902, 1903, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Report of Foochow Missionary Hospital, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - "Loose Leaves from Missionaries' Diaries", Nos. 1,2,4-6, 1917-1920 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Foochow Messenger (21 issues), 1904-1940 (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - Primers for Romanized Chinese, by Hannah C. Woodhall, 1908, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - Foochow Mission souvenir booklet, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - Fukien Mission Christmas greeting booklet with info re. missionaries, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - "The Foochow Mission 1847-1895", by C.C. Baldwin, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - "Christian Youth in Modern China - Foochow", 1932 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - "Comments on 'Re-Thinking Missions' from Fukien, China", 1933 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - "Glimpses of the American Board at Work in Fukien, China", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - "Introducing the American Board Missionaries of Fukien, China", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - "Youth", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - Letter from Wen Shan Girls School, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - Questionnaire from Interchurch World Movement of North America, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - Foochow College, 1910-1926 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - Re. ABCFM work in China
    - Program for 106th annual meeting of ABCFM (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Letter to missionaries of ABCFM in China, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - "The American Board Missions in China", 1928 (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Circular letter from H. Matthews, ABCFM Secretary for China, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - "Our Medical Missions in China", 1928 (Box 9, Folder 134)